American Song Sheets, 1850-1870 M1628.2.A5
Lilly Library
American Song Sheets
1850-1870
1999
Lilly Library
M1628.2.A5
459 Items
This collection consists of American song sheets without music from the mid-19th century.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Historical Note
Most of the song sheets were published or printed by J. Andrews and H. De Marsan of New York and J. H. Johnson of Philadelphia. Some have the ink stamp of T. C. Boyd, 228 Montgomery, San Francisco. The list was compiled by the Zamboni & Huntington, booksellers.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by song title.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of American song sheets without music from the mid-19th century. Included are ballads, patriotic songs, Irish songs, love songs, etc. Most of the items have illustrated borders, some of which are colored. The entry for each item includes a caption title; any composer, performer or author information from the piece; the first line of the text, number of verses and chorus if present; name of melody; place and publisher or printer; date if given; printing details, such as border design; and a reference to Edwin Wolf's American song sheets, slip ballads, and poetical broadsides 1850-1870: a catalogue of the collection of the Library Company of Philadelphia.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1999
American Song Sheets
- 1. Acrostic. Mary, Wilt Thou Have Me? - Mary, tho' I'm doomed to languish (5 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Not in Wolf.
- 2. Adolpheus Snow. - White folks, listen to me now (5 verses.) Air. - "Blow, ye Winds, I, O." New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. See Wolf 16.
- 3. Agnes May. - I kissed her lip and left her side (3 verses.) New York: H. Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 4. Aileen Astore - Oh! blessings for ever on Aileen Astore! (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 24.
- 5. All among the Hay. - Though I am what is called a "swell" (5 verses, chorus, spoken part.) Written by Wallace Markham. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with battle scenes in lower comers. Not in Wolf.
- 6. All Round My Hat. - All round my hat I vears a green villow (6 verses, spoken part.) No. 331. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Pat and Mike. Not in Wolf.
- 7. All's for the Best. - All 's for the best! be sanguine and cheerful (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 32.
- 8. The American Boy. - "Father look up and see the flag (8 verses.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Wavy-line with ornamental corners. Wolf 35b.
- 9. American Drinks. - The other night I'd been indulging -which I own is very silly (4 verses and chorus.) Sung by W. F. Sinclair, the Greatest Serio-Comic Singer in the United States. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. Not in Wolf.
- 10. An Angel Form. - An Angel Form, in dreams beheld (2 verses.) Second song: "Care Flies the Brain." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 42.
- 11. Annie I Have Missed You. - Dear Annie, it is you there, safe and well alone (3 verses.) Air... "Willie we have missed you." By Frederick S. English. New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 44.
- 12. Annie of the Vale. - The young stars are glowing (2 verses and chorus.) Words by G. P. Morris; music by J. R. Thomas. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 47.
- 13. Annie of the Vale. - The young stars are glowing (2 verses and chorus.) Words by G. P. Morris; music by J. R. Thomas. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 47.
- 14. Answer to a Thousand a Year. - Have you heard the strange news just came down, Gaffer Green (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 53.
- 15. Aunt Dinah. - I knew an old nigger Aunty once (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 16. Banks of Allan Water. - On the banks of Allan Water (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 17. Banks of Claudy. - It was on a summer 's morning all in the month of May (7 verses.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Wavy lines top and bottom of text. Not in Wolf.
- 18. Banks of Claudy. -It was on a summers morning all in the month of May (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Dc Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 19. The Banks of Sweet Dundee. - It is of a farmer's daughter, so beautiful I'm told (10 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 20. Banks of the Old Mohawk. - On the banks of the Old Mohawk (3 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 21. The Bard's Legacy. - When in death I shall calm recline (3 verses.) Second song: "The Lover's Wish." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 85a.
- 22. Bashful Young Man. - They say I shall get over it, but no, I never can (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 87b.
- 23. The Batchellor. - The batchelor sits in is dreary room (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Yankee pedlar, colored. Wolf 75a.
- 24. Battle of Bull-Run. - Our gallant soldiers they are gone and left their friends to mourn (8 verses.) Dedicated to the 69th Regiment, N.Y.S.M. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. See Wolf 95.
- 25. Beautiful Nell. - Don't talk to me of pretty girls! (6 verses and chorus.) Published with music by C. W. A. Trumpler. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Lines at top and bottom of text, one dotted. See Wolf 119.
- 26. The Belles of the 'Bus. - T'other day I indulged in an omnibus ride (6 verses.) Air: "The Mistletoe Bough. (The Old Oak Chest." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 129.
- 27. Be Quiet, Do, I'll Call My Mother. - As Kate was sitting in a wood (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 116.
- 28. Billy Barlow. - Oh, good evening, gentlemen. how do you do? (10 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 142.
- 29. Black Ey'd Susan. - All in the Downs the fleet was moor'd (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 153.
- 30. Black Eyed Susan. - All in the Downs the fleet was moor'd (8 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 153.
- 31. Blue Violets. - Blue violets, blue violets, beautiful blue violets (2 verses.) As sung by Charles Melville, the celebrated Balladist and Tenor vocalist. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 163a.
- 32. Bonaparte's Farewell. - Farewell to the land, where the gloom of my glory (3 verses.) Air.: "Captain O'Kean." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. Wolf 174.
- 33. Bonnie Jamie. - The twilight hour is stealing (5 verses.) By James Robinson. Respectfully dedicated to my friend, Sergeant Wheeler, U.S.A.... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 176.
- 34. Brave Boys. - Heavily falls the rain (4 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by Henry C. Work. Published by H. M. Higgins.... Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 196h.
- 35. Brooks's Canada Song. - To Canada Brooks was asked to go (6 verses.) Air - "The Cork Leg. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 211.
- 36. Bruce's Address to His Army. - Scots, wha hae wi' Wallace bled! (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. See Wolf 215.
- 37. Bucanier's Bride. - Away, away o'er the boundless deep (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Wolf 216.
- 38. Bummers, Come and Meet Us. -McClellan is our leader now, we've had our last retreat(7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 225 a or b.
- 39. Burial of Sir John Moore. - Not a drum was heard nor a funeral note (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Wolf 227.
- 40. By the Margin of Fair Zurich's Waters. - By the margin of fair Zurich's waters (2 verses.) New York: H. Dc Marsan, © 1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 41. By the Sad Sea-Waves. - By the sad sea-waves (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. See Wolf 232.
- 42. The Carrier Dove. - Fly away to my native land, sweet Dove (3 verses.) N.p.: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrew's ivy. Wolf 255a.
- 43. Carry the News to Mary. -Oh! Martha wept and Mary cried (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Charley Howard - Music by Walter Bray. Arranged by Eddie Fox. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 275.
- 44. Charming Jane Louisa. - It was in the merry month of June, when woods and fields were flowery (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 285.
- 45. Cheer for the Pilots. - The sturdy Pilots put to sea (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, with war scenes in lower comers, colored. See Wolf 293.
- 46. Christmas Carol. - The cold wind sweeps the branches bare (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 47. Come Home, Father. - Father, dear father, come home with me now (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 353.
- 48. Come to de Old Gum Tree. - Come to de old Gum Tree (6 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 49. Come Wake Up, My Lady Love. - Come lend an ear, my lub, to me (4 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 362.
- 50. The Constitution! - Oh God, preserve the Union (3 verses and chorus.) National Anthem written, composed and respectfully dedicated to the President and people of the United States, by F. Widdows. Sung by James Dunn. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Wolf 380.
- 51. The Crow Family. - I went from here to Washington a short time ago (7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 408.
- 52. Cruelty to Johnny! - Cruel wos de Captain vot took my Shon vrom me (4 verses and chorus.) [Philadelphia]: Johnson, n.d. See Wolf 409.
- 53. Cum Plung Gum. - I wish I was a turtle dove (4 verses and chorus.) Original Song and dance by Joe Murphy, of San Francisco, Cal. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Not in Wolf.
- 54. Daylight Is on the Sea. - Daylight is on the sea! (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 441.
- 55. The Dearest Spot on Earth to Me Is Home, Sweet Home. - The dearest spot of earth to me (2 verses.) Second song: "Welcome, Welcome Home." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 452a.
- 56. Dearest, Then I'll Love Thee More. - Yes, I love thee, and how dearly (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Auner and Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 57. Dear Mother I've Come Home to Die. - Dear mother, I remember well (3 verses and chorus.) No.855. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1467r (under "Mother, I've Come Home to Die")
- 58. Dear Old Hag! - See the Flag! the dear old Flag (4 verses and chorus.) Composed and dedicated to the Soldiers of the Unit. Stat. By Wm. B. Bradbury. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. Wolf 449c.
- 59. The Declaration. - We come, we come, a little band (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. Wolf 465a.
- 60. Dina's Wedding. - Hurrah! hurrah! the day is come (3? verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: G. S. Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 479.
- 61. A Dollar or Two. - With cautious steps, we tread on our way through (3 verses and chorus.) As sung nightly, with tremendous applause, by Mrs. W. Jones in the drama of "Fast women" at the New Bowery Theatre.... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 503.
- 62. Donnelly & Cooper, That Fought on Kildare. - Come all you true bred Irishmen, I hope you will draw near (8 verses.) [Philadelphia]: Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.
- 63. Don't You Go, Tommy. - You'll miss it, my boy, now mind what I say (3 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by C. T. Lockwood. Copied from the "Pulling hard against the Sream [sic] Songster,".... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 511.
- 64. Donybrook Fair. - Once I went to Donybrook, that good old Irish fair, sirs (8 verses and chorus.) Air - "Limerick Races." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 512.
- 65. Do You Ask Me if I Love You! - Do you ask me: if I love you? (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 496a.
- 66. The Dream of Bonaparte. - One night, sad and languid, I went to my bed (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 523.
- 67. Drover Boy. - I'm a merry heart'd mountain drover boy (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 527.
- 68. Drunkard's Lone Child. - Out in the gloomy night sadly I roam (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. See Wolf 534.
- 69. The Dumb Scold. -There lived an English blade, who loved a pretty maid (6 verses.) Air -"Cowskeen Lawn." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 538.
- 70. Ellsworth's Avengers! - Down where the patriot army (5 verses and chorus.) Air: "Annie Lisle." By A. L. Hudson. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 562.
- 71. The Englishman. - There's a land that bears a well known name (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 569.
- 72. Erin's Green Shore. - One evening so late as I rambled (4 verses.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.
- 73. The Escape of Stephens, the Fenian Chief. New Version of Shan Van Vocht. - Perhaps you'd like to know (9 verses.) With narrative preceding text, beginning: "The only exciting topic...." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 576.
- 74. Ever of Thee. - Ever of thee I am fondly dreaming (2 verses.) As Sung by John Hasset. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 581.
- 75. Every Bullet Has Its Billet - I'm a tough true hearted sailor (3 verses.) A song by Mr. Charles Swain, at Jenkins' Concert Saloon Seventh & Chestnut Streets. [Philadelphia: Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 582a.
- 76. Fairy Dell! - Wilt thou meet me in the fairy dell, love (3 verses and chorus.) A Companion to "Hazel Dell." Philadelphia: J. J. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 595.
- 77. False One I Love Thee Still. - Still so gently o'er me stealing (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments. See Wolf 1012.
- 78. Fanny Gray. - Well, well, sir, so you've come at last, I thought you'd come no more (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 604.
- 79. Fare Thee Well Kitty Dear. - I saw the smile of evening die (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 607.
- 80. Farewell! Dearest Maiden. - Farewell! dearest maiden (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Not in Wolf.
- 81. Farewell to the Home of My Childhood. - Farewell to the home of my childhood (2 verses.) With second song: "Saucy Kate." Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 82. The Farmer Sat in His Easy Chair. - The farmer sat in his easy chair (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. See Wolf 613.
- 83. The Farmer's Boy. - The sun had gone down behind yon hill (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 612b.
- 84. The Farmer's Daughter. - It is of a rich farmer, I dare not tell his name (10 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Not in Wolf.
- 85. Father Macshane. - Old father Macshane hed was holy and fat (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 618a.
- 86. The Father of All Songs. - And come all, you lads and lasses, wherever you may be (5 verses.) Composed by Wm. Dunne. Air - "The Glorious Sixty-Ninth." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 619a.
- 87. The Father of All Songs. - And come all, you lads and lasses, wherever you may be (5 verses.) Air - "The Glorious 69th." Number 902. [Boston?]: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 619.
- 88. The Fenian Brigade. - 0 ye, Sons of Green Erin, assemble (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "Red, White and Blue." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Not in Wolf.
- 89. The Fenian Men. - See who come over the red-blossomed heather! (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 627.
- 90. Few Days No.2. - This world is coming to an end, few days-few days (5 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 629a.
- 91. The Fireman's Boy. - Mother, look out and see that light (22 verses.) Air - "The American Boy." N.p., n.d. See Wolf 642.
- 92. The Fireman's Death. - He slept, and o'er his dauntless brow (3 verses and choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 643b.
- 93. The Flag with the Thirty-four Stars. - The Rebels sing the "Bonnie Blue Flag, " (5 verses and chorus.) New York: Charles Magnus, n.d. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 109A?, colored. Wolf 654g(?).
- 94. The Flower of the Land. -The Sun-burst has dawned over all the glad mountains (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "Jessie, the Flower of Dumblane." - Sung by G. W. Gill. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 662.
- 95. How Gently Sweet Afton. - Flow gently sweet Afton among thy green braes (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 661.
- 96. Folks that Put on Airs. - Oh White Folks listen will you now this darkey's going to sing (6 verses and chorus.) No 45. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 97. Fond Hearts at Home. - When I left the dear home of my father's (3 verses.) No.1.66. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley kissing cupids. See Wolf 666.
- 98. The Four Leaved Shamrock. - I'll seek a four leaved shamrock (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 670a.
- 99. Fourth of July Song. - We hail, once again, the glad day that gave (3 verses.) Air: "Star-Spangled Banner." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. Wolf 672a.
- 100. Free and Easy Still. - I'm the lad that '5 free and easy (7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 679.
- 101. Friendship and Love. - Of every sensation true joy can impart (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 692.
- 102. Gal from the South. - My Massa had a colored gal (3 verses and chorus.) [New York?]: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 698.
- 103. Gentle Jenny Gray. - My heart is sad, I'll tell you why (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by Mr. Joseph Murphy, of Wood & Christy's Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 731.
- 104. Gentle Maggie. - On an Island in the old Mohawk (3 verses and chorus.) Words by John Miller. Music composed and Arranged by Frank Mosier. As sung by the Mohawk Chorals of Cohoes, N.Y. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 732.
- 105. Gipsey Davy. - There was a lord, a high born lord (5 verses and chorus.) With second song: "Going Round the Horn." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Not in Wolf.
- 106. The Gipsey Girl. - My father was king of the gipsies you know (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 107. Give Me a Cot in the Valley I Love. - Give me a cot in the valley I love (2 verses.) Second song: "The Cot Where I Was Born." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 751c.
- 108. God Will Care for Mother Now. - Weep no more, 0 nobly fallen! (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "Who will care for Mother now?" By Louise Barrows. No.901. [Boston?]: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 775.
- 109. The Good-Bye at the Door. - Of all the mem'ries of the past (2 verses.) Second song: "'Twas Rank and Fame." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 791.
- 110. Good News from Home. - Good news from home - good news for me (3 verses and chorus.) No.154. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley kissing cupids. See Wolf 784.
- 111. Good News from Home. - Good news from home - good news for me (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 784.
- 112. The Grave of Bonaparte. -On a lone barren isle, where the wild roaring billow (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 805.
- 113. The Great Prize Fight. - Sullivan made a match to fight (8 verses and chorus.) Air -"Camptown Races." Following title: "Which took place at Boston Corners, Oct. 12th, 1853." [New York: Andrews], n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 817a.
- 114. The Grecian Bend [Nos. 1 and 21. - The ladies want something new (4 verses and chorus) and The world is taken all aback (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 115. The Grecian Bend. No.3. - There was a young lady who in Gotham did dwell (8 verses and choruses, moral.) Air - "Vilikins and his Dinah." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 116. The Green above the Red. - I am an Irish hero, that the English ne'er can frighten (3 verses and chorus.) Air: "There's Whiskey in the Jar." Composed and sung by Wm. H. Lindsey. Dedicated to St. Lawrence Circle of F.B. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. Not in Wolf.
- 117. The Green Bushes. - I'll buy you new bavers and fine silken gowns (4 verses.) Second song: "Blow, Gentle, Gales." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 822.
- 118. The Handsome Cabin Boy. - It is of a pretty female, as you shall understand (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 836.
- 119. Hans Dunder Has Gone for a Solger. - I'd traveled dis Countree there und here (5 verses and chorus.) Composed and sung by P. Bradel Jr. better known as Brudder Bones, Comic Singer of Avenue B. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 840.
- 120. Happy Haidee. - Gentle, gentle is the beam (2 verses and chorus.) As sung by Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 843a.
- 121. Happy Land of Canaan. - You may talk about de times (4 verses and chorus.) No.537. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 848.